Guide to the Giuliano Garavini Collection AD.MC.038
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Minutes of OPEC meetings, 1980-1985; 87 Megabytes in 20 PDF documents.
  - 75th meeting: Minutes of the Seventy-Fifth (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, Vienna, October 3 - 4, 1985 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_097)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Observer: Mexico. One of the primary topics discussed was the request of some member states (Iraq, Ecuador, Qatar, Gabon, and the United Arab Emirates) for an increase in their production quotas. The meeting agreed to maintain the total production ceiling of 16 million barrels, but to reallocate quotas among member states at a future date. Reports of the Ministerial Executive Council and the Ministerial Monitoring Committee were discussed as well.
    PDF, 74 pages, 3 MB.
  - 76th meeting: Minutes of the Seventy-Sixth (76th) Meeting of the Conference, Geneva, December 7 - 9, 1985 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_098)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Observers: Malaysia, Mexico. Topics included approval of the 1986 budget, review of the reports of the 63rd meeting of the Economic Commission Board and the Ministerial Monitoring Committee. Given the status of the market and the increasing decline in production by OPEC member states, concern was raised that OPEC needed to do more to capture a larger share of the market, and set up a committee to examine what measures OPEC could take to do so.
    PDF, 95 pages, 7 MB.
- Minutes of OPEC meetings, 1986; 69.5 Megabytes in 17 PDF documents.
  - 77th meeting (1): Minutes of the 77th (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference (part I), Geneva, March 16 - 24, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_099)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The 77th meeting was divided into two parts, one that met in Geneva over a week in March 1986, and the second half that resumed in Geneva a month later. During the first meeting, which c consisted of ten sessions, reports of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee, the Special Ministerial Committee, and the Minsterial Executive Committee were presented and discussed, with the main topics being the production ceiling, price differentials, and per barrel price in response to changes in the market since their last meeting, and ensuing losses in revenue to member states.
    PDF, 162 pages, 11 MB.
  - 77th meeting (1): Report: "Current Costs of Oil Production and Production Profiles in North Sea and USA, 1985-1990," OPEC Secretariat, Research Division, March 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_100)
    PDF, 41 pages, 2 MB.
  - 77th meeting (1): Report: "The World Oil Market: Immediate Prospects," OPEC Secretariat, Research Division, March 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_101)
  - 77th meeting (2): Minutes of the 77th (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, (part II), Geneva, April 15 - 21, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_102)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The conference continued its meeting in eight further sessions in which they discussed various strategies for defending OPEC's market share, set further production ceilings, discussed outreach to various non-OPEC oil producing nations (such as Mexico, Malaysia, Oman, Angola, Egypt), seeking to coordinate actions, and the meeting condemned the U.S. aerial attack on member state Libya.
    PDF, 105 pages, 7 MB.
  - 78th meeting (1): Minutes of the 78th Meeting of the Conference (part I), Brioni, June 25 - 30, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_103)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the Financial and Auditors' reports for 1985, discussion of the reports of the 64th meeting of the Economic Commission Board, the Ministerial Monitoring Committee, and the Group of Five Ministers. The latter report detailed the efforts of committee members to reach out to the governments of several non-OPEC oil producing countries (Norway, Mexico, Malaysia, Brunei, USSR, Angola, Egypt) in order to discuss how they could induce them to follow policies in terms of production and pricing that were more in alignment with those of OPEC. The bulk of the meeting though concerned discussions of production ceilings, quotas, and pricing of member states within OPEC. Also included is the text of the opening speech by Andrej Ocvirk, president of the Federal Committee for Energy and Industry of Yugoslavia.
    PDF, 137 pages, 9 MB.
  - 78th meeting (2): Minutes of the Seventy-Eighth Meeting of the Conference (part II), Geneva, July 28 - August 5, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_104)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The bulk of the meeting involved discussed on the contentious issues of quotas among member nations, as well as pricing and production ceilings.
    PDF, 89 pages, 6 MB.
  - 78th meeting (2): Paper: "Fuel Competitiveness", [July 14, 1986] (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_105)
    PDF, 10 pages, 310 KB.
  - 78th meeting (2): Paper: "The Impact of the USD$ 17-19 BBL Price Range on OPEC Oil", [July 25, 1986] (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_106)
    Note:
    Handwritten note on first page stating: "Prepared by Dr. A. Parra and M. Slotinfemi [sp?]. Presented on 25/7/86 to conference."
    PDF, 24 pages, 868 KB.
  - 79th meeting: Minutes of the Seventy-Ninth (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, Geneva, October 6 - 22, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_107)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The continued discussion of quotas and pricing occupied the bulk of the meeting, with the decision to extend the temporary ceiling on production set at the previous meetings, along with corresponding quotas amongo member states.
    PDF, 207 pages, 14 MB.
  - 79th meeting: Report: "Criteria for Allocation of Production Quota," OPEC Secretariat, Research Division, October 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_108)
    PDF, 18 pages, 932 KB.
  - 79th meeting: Report: "Oil Pricing System," OPEC Secretariat, Research Division, October 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_109)
  - 80th meeting: Minutes of the Eightieth Meeting of the Conference, Geneva, December 11 - 20, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_110)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the continued discussion of production ceilings, quotas, and pricing, with review of reports by the Ministerial Monitoring Committee, the Economic Commission Board, the Ministerial Committee on Pricing, and the Ministerial Committee on Quotas. The topic of adopting a fixed price per barrel, raised at the previous meeting, was adopted, at the price of $18 per barrel.
    PDF, 151 pages, 10 MB.
  - 80th meeting: Report: "Report of OPEC's Ministerial Committee on Pricing," Quito, 14 November 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_111)
    PDF, 4 pages, 200 KB.
  - 80th meeting: Report: "Report of the Meeting of the Experts' Committee on the OPEC Pricing System to the Ministerial Committee on Pricing," Vienna, November 29 - 30, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_112)
    PDF, 28 pages, 736 KB.
  - 80th meeting: Report: "Report of the Ministerial Committee on Quotas," Geneva, December 11, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_113)
    PDF, 6 pages, 198 KB.
  - 80th meeting: Report: "Meeting of Experts on Differentials," Geneva, December 12, 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_114)
    PDF, 12 pages, 262 KB.
  - 80th meeting: Documents: Member countries proposals on quotas, June - December 1986 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_115)
    Note
    Consists of letters, telexes, charts, statistics, submitted to Secretariat by various member countries, as background information for their positions on whether or not production quotas should be raised.
    PDF, 67 pages, 2 MB.
- Other OPEC documents, 1960 - 1997; 25 Megabytes in 2 PDF documents.
  - OPEC Official Resolutions and Press Releases, 1960 - 1990 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_116)
    PDF, 325 pages, 19 MB.
  - OPEC Official Resolutions and Press Releases, 1990 - 1997 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_117)